<chapter id="chart_introduction">
	<title> FusionChart Free</title>

	<section id="chart_fusionchart_intro">
		<title> Introduction</title>
		<para>
			FusionChart Free is a chart component based on open source (MIT/GPL dual license) Flash made by InfoSoft Global.
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
      		<listitem>
        		<para><emphasis role="bold">Provision of various chart types</emphasis></para>
        		<para>
        			Various 22 types of charts are provided with sophisticated design.
        			Since details of charts with the same shape can be adjusted through various style options provided by FusionChart,
        			more differentiated charts can be produced.
        		</para>
        		<para>Types of charts: column, line, pie, bar, area, stacked, candlestick, funnel charts, etc.</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para><emphasis role="bold">Convenient data linkage</emphasis></para>
        		<para>
        			Since charts are made based on XML, they can be developed not subject to a specific language.
        			The charts can be used in PHP, ASP.NET, JSP, ColdFusion, Python, RoR, simple HTML pages, and even in PowerPoint presentations.
        		</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para><emphasis role="bold">Minimized server load</emphasis></para>
        		<para>The component developed based on Flash has a small volume and partly supports Ajax.</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
      			<para><emphasis role="bold">FusionChart Free for jQuery</emphasis></para>
      			<para>
      				Ajax support was improved by providing the jQuery plugin, and the chart component can be integrated in the web pages with a simple and consistent code.
      			</para>
      		</listitem>
    	</itemizedlist>
    	<para><emphasis role="bold">Others</emphasis></para>
    	<para>
    		There is also a commercial chart component that provides additional functions differentiated from FusionChart Free (e.g. image/PDF/CSV/XML conversion function, various visual effects, various chart types, etc.)
    		
    	</para>
	</section>
</chapter>