<chapter id="jdbcsupport_injectionandlogging_architecture">
		<title>Architecture</title>


		<section id="jdbcsupport_injectionandlogging_architecture_base">
        	<title>Architecture</title>
        	
        	<para>dataSource  - AOP Method Interceptor - JdbcAspect (p6spy connection wrapping)</para>
        	
        	<para>InjectionPatternPostProcessor / CompleteQueryPostProcessor- registered as Spring bean and and conduct DI on jdbcAspect. </para>
        	
        	<para>
        		P6Factory provides P6Connection and P6PreparedStatement applying InjectionPatternPostProcessor and CompleteQueryPostProcessor 
        		features regarding getConnection and getPreparedStatement taking place at user jdbc.app. 
        	</para>
        	
        	<para>
        		According to JDBC usage types, points on connection.prepareStatement(sql) and preparedStatement.execute(sql)can process 
        		InjectionPattern and CompleteQuery (by delivering them with logging or other methods)
        	</para>
        	
			<para>P6Spy Connection Wrapping</para>
        	<itemizedlist>
          		<listitem>
            		<para>P6Factory Extension </para>
            	</listitem>
            	<listitem>
            		<para>P6Connection Extension </para>
            	</listitem>
            	<listitem>	
            		<para>P6 Statement/PreparedStatement/CallableStatement Extension </para>
          		</listitem>
        	</itemizedlist>
		</section>



		<section id="jdbcsupport_injectionandlogging_architecture_injection">
        	<title>InjectionPatternPostProcessor</title>

        	<para>
        		Whether SQL Injection pattern exists is detected and warning regarding this is processed. return void
        		<programlisting language="java"><![CDATA[public void warningPattern(String sql)]]></programlisting>
        	</para>
        	
        	<para>
        		After replacing Injection pattern, modified sql statement is returned.
        		<programlisting language="java"><![CDATA[public String replacePattern(String sql)]]></programlisting>
        	</para>
        	
        	<para>
        		Various warning/replace patterns are set in the format of regular expression. By defining these patterns as property of bean 
        		setup file, warn logging and sql replace are handles for matching. 
   				cf.) If the above Interface is matched, implementation can be freely modified depending on site characters. 
        	</para>
      	</section>
      	
		<section id="jdbcsupport_injectionandlogging_architecture_completequery">
        	<title>CompleteQueryPostProcessor</title>

        	<para>
        		CompleteQuery is reprocessed (ex. SQL Logging).
        		<programlisting language="java"><![CDATA[public void processCompleteQuery(String sql)]]></programlisting>
        	</para>

        	<para>
        		Default execution means that CompleteQuery logs via commons logging. 
				cf.) If the above Interface is matched, implementation can be freely modified depending on site characters. 
        	</para>
      	</section>
</chapter>
