<chapter id="flex_query_introduction">
	<title>Introduction</title>
	<para>
		Adobe Flex is RIA development solution which makes flash screen through defining MXML.
		As compiled result is made in Flash file, if Flash Player is installed, it can be executed in any browser and
		colorful and various screen can be provided like Flash screen.		
	</para>
	<para>
		Although HTTPService basically provided in Flex alone enables the development of Web Application, 
		but it has many limitations in that the data transmission is made in xml.
		Using BlazeDS enables data transmission between Client and Server by using RemotingService, MessageService as well as HTTPService.		
	</para>
	<para>
		Spring BlazeDS Integration provides functions that can simplify complex and difficult configurations
		when developing  Flex Web Application using BlazeDS and Spring Framework.		
	</para>
	<section id="flex_query_introduction_sec001">
		<title>Flex</title>
		<section id="flex_query_introduction_sec001_001">
		<title>How Flex Works</title>
		<para>
			Flex is basically composed of Action Script, MXML, Asset(CSS, Image)
			and compiled SWF file is executed at Flash Player.			
		</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="../image/flex-query/flex_application.jpg"	align="center" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section id="flex_query_introduction_sec001_002">
		<title>MXML Compile and Flex Builder</title>
		<para>
			To compile MXML file, you can execute command  mxmlc.exe provided in Flex SDK as the following.			
		</para>
		<programlisting language="java">mxmlc -file -specs Main.mxml</programlisting>
		<para>
			Flex Builder 3 is IDE for Flex development and automatically compiles mxml file as mxmlc and compc compiler are included.
			There are independent execution version and Eclipse Plugin version in Flex Builder 3.
			independent execution version requires additionally Eclipse installation, but cannot use JDT(Java Development Tools).			
		</para>
		<para>
			Flex Builder 3 provides functions that are needed for development such as debugging, auto complete, monitoring, etc. in addition to auto MXML compile
			and also provides design view for better component design.			
		</para>
		</section>
	</section>
		<section id="flex_query_introduction_sec002">
		<title>BlazeDS</title>
		<para>
			As HTTPService, data transmission method basically provided in Flex, transmits data in xml, 
			there are some security issues as it is not suitable for mass-capacity data transmission and url information is created 
			within the source code of MXML.
			BlazeDS is an Opensource S/W provided in Adobe for data transmission between Client and Server.
			BlazeDS is largely composed of the following.			
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Client</emphasis> : RemoteObject, HTTPService, WebService, Producer, Consumer
				 </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Server</emphasis> : BlazeDS library, BlazeDS configuration file, MessageBrokerServlet
				 </para>
			</listitem>
  		</itemizedlist>
  		<para>
  			 BlzeDS provides RPC(HTTPService, WebService, RemoteObject) Service, Messaging Service
  			 in a data transmission method between Client and Server and.
  			For more information in each service, refer to <link linkend="flex_query_dataintegraion_sec002">Data integration using BlazeDS</link>/.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>