<chapter id="utilsystem_architecture">
	<title> Architecture</title>
	<section id="utilsystem_architecture_sigar">
		<title> SigarAccessor Architecture</title>
		<para>
			Anyframe provides SigarAccessor to simplify the initial environment setup of SIGAR that uses JNI library.
		</para>
		<para>The following diagram is Anyframe System Architecture for using Sigar.</para>
		<mediaobject>
	      <imageobject>
	        <imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/util-system/util-system-architecture-sigar.jpg" />
	      </imageobject>
	    </mediaobject>
    	<para>SIGAR (System Information Gatherer and Reporter) is an open source (Apache License, Version 2.0) library that supports various platforms/languages
    	 and is a command-line tool to accessing OS and hardware level information in Java, Perl, and .Net.</para>
    	 <para>
			SIGAR is a core sub-project of Hyperic HQ, which is a System Management/Monitoring Tool Suite,
			and was made at first to overcome the difficulty in easily accessing and measuring the low-level hardware/OS information on the Java platform.
			Hyperic has been acquired by SpringSource, and the license policy has been recently changed to Apache License, thus eliminating limitations in its use.
			Based on JNI (Java Native Interface), it implements system processing differing according to platforms through quick low-level processing using Native library, 
			and through Java JNI Binding is flexibly integrated into the Java environment.
		</para>
		<para>Major functions provided by SIGAR are as follows.</para>
    	<itemizedlist>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>system memory, SWAP, cpu, load average, uptime</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>memory information for each process, identification and authentication information, condition, arguments, environment</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>file system information</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>network information and setup</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>TCP and UDP connection table information</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>network route table information</para>
      		</listitem>
    	</itemizedlist>
        <para>Fore easy usage of various functions of Sigar, Anyframe provides SigarAccessor and enables easy access to system, network, and file information.
        	The functions of SigarAccessor are as follows.
        </para>
	    <itemizedlist>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>initialization of Sigar running environment</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>basic system resource gathering and initialization</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>update of resources changed in real time</para>
      		</listitem>
    	</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="utilsystem_architecture_filemonitor">
		<title>File Monitor Architecture</title>
		<para>
			Anyframe provides the function of regularly monitoring the events of file changes within directories by generating FileWatcherThread provided by Sigar through a utility called FileMonitor.
			The information on added/modified/deleted files within the monitored directories is logged using log4j.(Various targets such as console, file and DB can be set up depending on Appender assignment.)
		</para>
		<para>The following diagram is Anyframe system architecture for FileMonitor.</para>
		<mediaobject>
	      <imageobject>
	        <imagedata align="center"  fileref="../image/util-system/util-system-architecture-filemonitor.jpg" />
	      </imageobject>
	    </mediaobject>
	</section>

	<section id="utilsystem_architecture_zip">
		<title>Zip Architecture</title>
		<para>Anyframe supports compression/decompression of files such as zip, tar and tar.gz using the Apache Commons Compress function. </para>
		<para>The following diagram is Anyframe system architecture for file compression/decompression.</para>
		<mediaobject>
	      <imageobject>
	        <imagedata align="center"  fileref="../image/util-system/util-system-architecture-zip.jpg" />
	      </imageobject>
	    </mediaobject>
	</section>

	<section id="utilsystem_architecture_shellscript">
		<title>Shell Script Architecture</title>
		<para>Anyframe provides the function to support flexibly Shell Script implementation and processing of the results in the Java environment. </para>
		<para>The following diagram is Anyframe system architecture for implementing Shell Script.</para>
		<mediaobject>
	      <imageobject>
	        <imagedata align="center"  fileref="../image/util-system/util-system-architecture-shellscript.jpg" />
	      </imageobject>
	    </mediaobject>
	</section>

</chapter>