<chapter id="jasperreports_integration_controller">
	<title>Controller</title>
	<para>
		Reporting functions provided in Anyframe basically include all the JasperReports functions, 
		but because integrated with Spring MVC, some JasperReports functions are not provided through Spring MVC. 
		In this case the developer has to extend the view class or do additional work to the Controller class. 
		In the cases below, Anyframe already provides the extended version to ease the additional work of developers.
    </para>

    <itemizedlist>
    	<listitem>
        	<para>
        		HTML Reporting- Partially in need of additional work by developer
        	</para>
      	</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <section id="jasperreports_integration_controller_html">
		<title>HTML Reporting</title>

		<para>
			To display image file in HTML, the view class provided by Spring MVC needs to be extended 
			and additional work needs to be done for the Controller class. 
			Expansion of the view class provided by Spring MVC is done by Anyframe, so it is not a concern for the developer. 
			However, additional work for the Controller class requires the developer to save request information of Controller that the developer is to develop in the Model object. 
			This work should be developed following the codes below.
      	</para>

      	<itemizedlist>
        	<listitem>
          		<para>
          			JasperReportsMultiFormatView expansion - After receiving session object through request as below within the rederReport method, save populatedReport value with attribute in object. 
          			This is needed to display image file during HTML Reporting. (Only for reference. In fact, the developer does not have anything to do.)
          			<programlisting language="java">protected void renderReport(JasperPrint populatedReport, Map model,
        HttpServletResponse response) throws Exception {
    // Check for request object and set image servlet
    if (model.containsKey("requestObject")) {
        HttpServletRequest request = (HttpServletRequest) model.get("requestObject");
        request.getSession().setAttribute(ImageServlet.DEFAULT_jasperreports_PRINT_SESSION_ATTRIBUTE,
                populatedReport);
    }
}</programlisting></para>
        	</listitem>

        	<listitem>
          		<para>
          			Additional work for <emphasis role="bold">Controller </emphasis> - To receive "requestObject" value from model object as above, 
          			the request object should be stored in the Controller class model object. 
          			Examples of ReportController class for reporting according to the product register status of each category is as follows.
          			<programlisting language="java">@Controller
public class ReportController extends MultiActionController {
    @RequestMapping("/testReport.*")
    public ModelAndView viewReport(HttpServletRequest request,
                                   HttpServletResponse response) 
    throws Exception {
    ...
      Map model = new HashMap();
      <emphasis role="bold"><emphasis>model.put</emphasis></emphasis>("format", format);
      <emphasis role="bold">model.put</emphasis>("<emphasis role="bold">requestObject</emphasis>", <emphasis
                role="bold">request</emphasis>);
        
      return new ModelAndView("reportView", model);
    }
}</programlisting>
				</para>
			</listitem>

        	<listitem>
				<para>
					Additional work for <emphasis role="bold">JSP </emphasis> - Examples for callingreEport on JSP are as follows. 
					Reports are called in testReport.html or testReport.pdf form.					
					<programlisting>
<![CDATA[<table class="table" border="1">
    <tr>
        <td class="ct_list_b"><b>Report Style</b></td>
        <td class="ct_list_b"><b>Report</b<>/td>
    </tr>
    <tr class="ct_list_pop">
        <td align="center"HTML></td>
        <td>
            <a href="${ctx}/reports/]]><emphasis role="bold">testReport.html</emphasis>"
                <![CDATA[<font color="blue">
                    <u>Show Product Report</u>
                </font>
            </a>                
        </td>
    </tr>
    <tr class="ct_list_pop">
        <td align="center">PDF</td>
        <td>
            <a href="${ctx}/reports/]]><emphasis role="bold">testReport.pdf</emphasis>"<![CDATA[>
                <font color="blue">
                    <u>Show Product Report</u>
                </font>
            </a>
        </td>
    </tr>
</table>]]>
</programlisting>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
</chapter>
