<chapter id="jasperreports_designer_installation">
	<title>Installation</title>
	<para>
		Next is the installation process of JasperReports. Instructions are separated into three stages:  <link linkend="jasperreports_designer_installation_download">Download</link>,
    	<link linkend="jasperreports_designer_installation_environment">Installation Environment</link>, and  
    	<link linkend="jasperreports_designer_installation_report">Report Designer</link> Installation. 
    	Here, JasperReports is integrated with Spring MVC, so instructions will be under the assumption that Spring of Anyframe and Spring MVC are already installed. 
    	Therefore, JasperReports should be installed after Anyframe is installed.
	</para>

	<section id="jasperreports_designer_installation_download">
		<title>Download</title>

      	<para>
      		The following are the basic files that need to be downloaded to use JasperReports.
      	</para>

      	<informaltable>
        	<tgroup cols="2">
				<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="4*"/>
				<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="6*"/>
          		<thead>
            		<row>
              			<entry align="center">File name</entry>

              			<entry align="center">Description</entry>

            		</row>
          		</thead>

          		<tbody>
            		<row>
             	 		<entry><ulink url="http://www.jasperassistant.com/download.html">JasperAssistant_3.1.1_Eclipse3.x.zip</ulink></entry>

 	             		<entry>[Required] JasperReports Report Designer Eclipse Plugin Installation File (Download Evaluation Version)</entry>

  	          		</row>

            		<row>
              			<entry><ulink url="http://get.adobe.com/kr/reader/">install_reader[Version]_en_[XXX].zip</ulink></entry>

              			<entry>[Required] Adobe Reader installation file for PDF file display</entry>

            		</row>
          		</tbody>
        	</tgroup>
		</informaltable>
    </section>

    <section id="jasperreports_designer_installation_environment">
		<title>Installation Environment</title>

      	<para>
      		Sample Application using JasperReports was tested in the environment described below. 
      		This manual will not explain how the below SW were installed. 
      		The following three should all be installed into the development environment before moving on to the next stage.  
      		Descriptions in this manual are based on the JDK 1.5 version.
      	</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
          		<para>
          			JDK 1.5
          		</para>
        	</listitem>

        	<listitem>
          		<para>
          			Web Container - Tomcat 6.0
          		</para>
        	</listitem>

        	<listitem>
          		<para>
          			DataBase - HsqlDB 1.8.0.10
          		</para>
        	</listitem>

        	<listitem>
          		<para>
          			Eclipse 3.5.0
          		</para>
        	</listitem>
      	</itemizedlist>

      	<para>
      		This document provides installation guidelines based on <ulink url="http://tomcat.apache.org/">Tomcat6.0</ulink> and
      		<ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/">eclipse 3.5.0 (including WTP)</ulink>
      	</para>

		<para>
			[Eclipse Home] hereafter refers to the route of eclipse based tool set provided by Anyframe. 
			Install Tomcat6.0 and register it as Eclipse Server Runtime. 
			If you have downloaded all the files marked [Required] on the above download table, execute AdbeRdr920_ko_KR.exe and install.
		</para>
    </section>

    <section id="jasperreports_designer_installation_report">
		<title>Report Designer Installation</title>

		<para>
			Various tools are provided to make developing XML file reports of JasperReports easier. 
			Various tools including free tools (iReport)and tools charged for (JasperAssistant) are available for use, 
			but here, the assumption will be that <emphasis role="bold">JasperAssistant</emphasis> is used.
      	</para>

     	<para>
     		[Reference]
     	</para>

      	<para>
      		* <emphasis role="bold">iReport :</emphasis>
      		<ulink url="http://jasperforge.org/projects/ireport">http://jasperforge.org/projects/ireport</ulink>
      		(free)
      	</para>

      	<para>
      		* <emphasis role="bold">JasperAssistant</emphasis> :
      		<ulink url="http://www.jasperassistant.com/">http://www.jasperassistant.com</ulink>
      		(Evaluation version of the 21th can be used if not purchased)
      	</para>

      	<para>
      		Currently, the JasperAssistant Eclipse plugin 3.1.1 version is being used.
      		Version updates of JasperAssistant are frequent, so if you are willing to download and install the latest version refer to the following websites.
      	</para>

      	<para>
      		* Homepage : <ulink url="http://www.jasperassistant.com/">http://www.jasperassistant.com</ulink>
      	</para>

      	<para>
      		* Download : <ulink url="http://www.jasperassistant.com/download.html">http://www.jasperassistant.com/download.html</ulink>
      	</para>

      	<para>
      		There are two ways to install JasperAssistant. One is to use the Eclipse Update Site, 
      		and the other is to download the deployed Eclipse Plugin file and copy it onto Eclipse.
      		Here, the installation instructions will be based on downloading the deployed file and copying it onto Eclipse.
      	</para>

      	<para>
      		Extract JasperAssistant_3.1.1_Eclipse3.x.zip into [Eclipse Home] folder and install. 
      		If Eclipse is already running, close and re-run.
      	</para>

		<section id="jasperreports_designer_installation_report_configuration">
        	<title>Configuration</title>

        	<para>
        		To use Eclipse Plugin JasperAssistant after installation, the following Configuration works should be done. 
        		To open the Configuration window, select <emphasis role="bold"><![CDATA[Window ->Preferences ->JasperAssistant]]></emphasis>.
			</para>

        	<itemizedlist>
          		<listitem>
            		<para>
            			License Information - If you have purchased JasperAssistant, enter the License Key in this page.
            		</para>
          		</listitem>

          		<listitem>
            		<para>
            			Console - [Use Default] Change JasperAssistant console window setting
            		</para>
          		</listitem>

          		<listitem>
            		<para>
            			Designer - [Use Default] Change Design Editor setting
            		</para>
          		</listitem>

          		<listitem>
            		<para>
            			Data Sources - Set to <emphasis role="bold">Required Setting</emphasis> before using Report Designer. 
            			Enter information to access data sources for report. 
            			In this case, four types of data sources (Empty Data Source, Database Data
            			Source, XML Data Source, Custom Data Source) are provided, but this manual will only touch upon Database Data Source setting. 
            			To access HSQLDB, enter information in Driver, URL, hsqldb jar file location, etc. as below.
           			</para>

          		    <mediaobject>
              			<imageobject>
               				 <imagedata align="center"
                           		fileref="../image/jasperreports/designer/jasperassistant2.jpg" />
              			</imageobject>
            		</mediaobject>
          		</listitem>

          		<listitem>
            		<para>
            			<![CDATA[Export - [Use Default] Change Export Setting (Used when executing File > Report Export..) is not necessary when using Report Designer, 
            			but when the Export function is used the location of PDF, Excel, HTML, etc. execution files should be clearly stated. 
            			Write C:\Program Files\Adobe\Reader 9.0\Reader\AcroRd32.exe, C:\Program Files\Internet Explorer\iexplore.exe in each Preview item.]]>
            		</para>
          		</listitem>
        	</itemizedlist>

        	<para>
        		JasperAssistant has been installed. 
        		Refer to <link linkend="jasperreports_designer_report">Report Designer</link> in this manual for ways to make report files with JasperAssistant.
       	 	</para>
      </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
