<chapter id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui">
	<title>Sample UI</title>
	<para>	 
	</para>
	
	<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_introduction">
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<para>
			Thirteen views are presented as samples. 
			When Anyframe MiPlatform UI Sample is executed, the menu is provided on the left. 
			Each view consists of functions that manage categories, communities, community postings, users, etc. 
			Each sample view shows how to use UI components, handle events, use script, structure Dataset to use common module provided by Anyframe, 
			process validation, etc. Detailed instructions on how to use each UI component can be found on the Help manual of MiPlatform PID.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui">
		<title>Set of Sample UI</title>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_grd">
			<title>01GRD – Sample1 (Search + Grid + Paging Control)</title>
			<para>
				The view on searching through community category lists and managing categories. 
				On the bottom of Grid is Paging Control. 
				Through Paging in this sample, data on a specific page can be retrieved to table by clicking page number.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui01.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						When you click the add button, a row is added to the grid to input information on creating a new category.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Category information can be modified directly on Grid.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you select a category from Grid and click delete, it will be deleted. 
						You can use the Shit of Ctrl key to select Multi Rows to delete many files at once.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The input, modification, delete, etc. of information can all be stored at once in table when clicking store.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>

		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_grdfrm">
			<title>02GRDFRM – Sample2 (Search + Grid +Input Form + Paging Control)</title>
			<para>
				View of searching through posting lists of communities, and managing postings. 
				Paging Control is on the bottom of the Grid.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui02.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						By selecting a posting on the list, you can read and modify the contents on the bottom input form.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you click the add button, a row is added and you can post a new message on the bottom empty input form.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you want to delete a posting from the Grid, select the posting and click delete. 
						Use the Shift or Ctrl key to select Multi Rows to delete many items at once.
						
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The input, modification, delete, etc. of information can be stored in table at all once by clicking store.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_grdpop">
			<title>03GRDPOP – Sample3 (Search + Grid + Input Form Popup + Paging Control)</title>
			<para>
				View of searching through community posting list, and managing postings. 
				Paging Control is on the bottom of the Grid.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui03.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						When you double-click a posting, you can read and modify the contents of posting through the popup window that appears.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						When you click the add button, a popup window will appear as an empty form on which you can write a new posting.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you want to delete a posting from the Grid, select the posting and click delete. 
						Use the Shift or Ctrl key to select Multi Rows to delete many items at once.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The input, modification, delete, etc. of information can be stored in table at all once by clicking store.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_grdtab">
			<title>04GRDTAB – Sample4 (Search + Upper Grid + Bottom Tab Input Form)</title>
			<para>
				View of searching and managing user list. There is a tab on the bottom to search detailed information of user.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui04.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you select user from the list, detailed information on the user can be read and modified on the bottom tab input form.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you push the add button a row is added to the Grid, and an empty tab input form appears on the bottom for adding new user.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you check the user checkbox and click delete, a user will be deleted
						The checkbox can be used to delete multiple users at once.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The input, modification, delete, etc. of information can be stored in table all at once by clicking store.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_grdtab2">
			<title>05GRDTAB – Sample5 (Search + Left Grid + Right Tab Input Form)</title>
			<para>
				View of searching and managing users. There is a tab to search user information on the right.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui05.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you select a user, you can search and modify detailed information of the user on the right tab input form.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you click the add button, a row is added to Grid and an empty tab input form appears on the right to add a new user.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you check the user checkbox and click delete, a user will be deleted
						The checkbox can be used to delete multiple users at once.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The input, modification, delete, etc. of information can be stored in table all at once by clicking store.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_grdgrd">
			<title>06GRDGRD – Sample6 (Left/Right Grid Item Transfer)</title>
			<para>
				A view of transferring community categories. 
				On the left is a list of communities in the computer category, 
				and on the right are communities in the car category. 
				The button at the center of the view is used to transfer the community. 
				This is a sample that shows left/right item transfer within the Grid.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui06.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						When you select a community from the list and click a button for moving to the right or left, the community moves.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Edited contents can all be stored at once in the table by clicking the store button.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_grdgrd2">
			<title>07GRDGRD – Sample7 (Search + Upper Master Grid + Bottom Sub Grid + Validation)</title>
			<para>
				View of searching community posting lists and managing postings. 
				You can render the the bottom category list by clicking the upper category list and using the category ID for filter() which is an internal Service API of MiPlatform. 
				Validation processing of input data is applied to the below community list.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui07.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you select a community on the upper Master Grid, a the list of postings appears on the bottom Sub Grid.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you click the add button, a row is added to sub grid for you to write a new posting.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Postings can be modified on Grid.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you wish to delete from Grid, check the user checkbox and click delete. 
						The checkbox can be used to delete several postings at once.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The input, modification, delete, etc. of information can be stored in table all at once by clicking store.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Validation processing using gfnValidate() which is a common script function of Grid input data, is applied.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_trvgrd">
			<title>08TRVGRD – Sample8 (Search + Tree + Grid + Tab Input Form Popup + Validation)</title>
			<para>
				View of searching team list with Tree, and managing the users of each team. 
				It introduces how to use Tree and Grid. 
				Validation processing for input data is applied.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui08.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you go to Tree on the left and select team, the user list of the team appears on the right Grid.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you double-click user from the list on the right, a tab input form popup window appears 
						for you to read and modify the detailed contents.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you click the add button, a popup window appears to add a new user.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you want to delete user from the Grid, select the user and click delete. 
						You can use the Shift of Ctrl key to select Multi Rows and delete many items at once.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The input, modification, delete, etc. of information can be stored in table all at once by clicking store.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Validation processing using gfnValidate() which is a common script function, is applied.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_trvfrm">
			<title>09TRVFRM – Sample9 (Search + Tree + Input Form)</title>
			<para>
				View of searching category and community list with Tree, and managing community information. 
				It introduces how to use Tree and input form.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui09.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you select category from the left Tree, category information appears on the right.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you select category from the left Tree, community information appears on the right.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						All edited community information is stored when clicking store button.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_ctggrd">
			<title>10CTGGRD – Sample10 (Category Division + Search + Grid)</title>
			<para>
				View of searching category community lists. 
				It provides instructions on making a category division table using Grid. 
				You can render the the bottom category list by clicking the upper category list and using the category ID for filter() which is an internal Service API of MiPlatform.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui10.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you select a category from the top, a community list appears on the bottom.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you click the add button, row is added for creating a new community.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Community information can be modified on Grid.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you wish to delete, check the user checkbox and click delete. 
						The checkbox can be used to delete multiple users at once.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Edited contents including the input, modification, deletion, etc. of information can all be stored at once in a table by clicking store.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_calmtly">
			<title>11CALMTLY – Sample11 (Monthly Calendar Using Grid)</title>
			<para>
				View of monthly schedule management. 
				Shows how to make a calendar using Grid.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui11.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Can search schedule by moving from month to month using button.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If a defined schedule exists, a detailed schedule will appear on a popup window when you double-click the date.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If a defined schedule does not exist, a popup window will appear to add a new schedule.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_calwkly">
			<title>12CALWKLY – Sample12 (Weekly Calendar Using Grid)</title>
			<para>
				View of weekly schedule. It shows how to use Grid to form a calendar.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui12.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use buttons to move from week to week to search weekly schedule.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If a defined schedule exists, a detailed schedule will appear on a popup window when you double-click the date.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If a defined schedule does not exist, a popup window will appear to add a new schedule.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mip_query_mipuisample_sampleui_setsampleui_fileatt">
			<title>13FILEATT - Sample13 (Attached File)</title>
			<para>
				View of the detailed information on posting with an ID of ‘POST-00001’. 
				It is a sample view that implements file attachment using file component and file dialog component. 
				The purpose of this sample is to introduce how to use file component and file dialog component, 
				so please note that this does not include implementation on processing mass storage files. 
				Processing speed can be impacted according to the network environment or size of attached file.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/mip-query/mipuisample/mipsampleui13.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you push the add button, a File Dialog window appears for attaching files.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						In this sample, the maximum limit for attached file size is 1MB.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you check the checkbox and click the download button, 
						a dialog appears for selecting the folder to store downloaded contents.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you double-click the attached file in the attached file list, 
						a dialog for selecting the location and name of downloaded file will appear.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you wish to delete, check the attached file checkbox and click delete. 
						The checkbox can be used to delete multiple files at once.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Edited contents can all be stored at once in table by clicking the store button.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>			
</chapter>