<chapter id="struts_architecture">
	<title>Architecture</title>

		<para>
			Struts Architecture is based on Model-View-Controller design pattern. 
			So, if you separate model and view, an environment that can form various presentations based on Single domain model is provided. 
			
		</para>

	<section id="struts_architecture_controller">
    <title>Controller Structure</title>

	    <para>
    		One controller is used according to the Front Controller pattern of Java EE. 
    		Therefore, services such as security, internationalization, and logging can be processed through Controller which is an advantage. 
    		It executes the following roles. 
    	</para>

    	<itemizedlist>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>Interrupts request that comes from client </para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>Mapping of each request to specific business logic </para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>Selects view based on the current situation and business logic processing results, and shows view to client </para>
      		</listitem>
    	</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="struts_architecture_requestflow">
    <title>Flow of Request</title>

    	<para>The following figure shows architecture when forming presentation layer using Struts</para>

	    <mediaobject>
	      <imageobject>
	        <imagedata align="center"
	                   fileref="../image/struts/struts_architecture.jpg" />
	      </imageobject>
	    </mediaobject>

    	<para>Executed in the following order when request is sent by client</para>

    	<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
        		<para>
        			When web application starts, Struts configuration file (struts-config.xml) loading is performed 
        			using servlet information set in web.xml.
        		</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>
        			Decide ActionMapping according to request from RequestProcessor defined in struts-config.xml. 
        		</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>
        			Execute execute() method of Action class according to URL and action mapping information defined in struts-config.xml.
        		</para>
      		</listitem>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>
        		Action execute() method calls business logic by connecting to business layer.
        		</para>
      		</listitem>
			<listitem>
        		<para>
                    Return ActionForward according to business logic execution result,
        			and Controller performs forwarding with the appropriate view according to return value.
        		</para>
      		</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
</chapter>
