<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY generic_implementation_domain SYSTEM "generic/domain.xml">
<!ENTITY generic_implementation_usage SYSTEM "generic/usage.xml">
<!ENTITY generic_implementation_test SYSTEM "generic/test.xml">
<!ENTITY generic_implementation_resources SYSTEM "generic/resources.xml">
]
>

<!--
		Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
		contributor license agreements. See the NOTICE file distributed with
		this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
		The ASF licenses this file to you under the Apache License, Version
		2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
		with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at

		http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0 Unless required by
		applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed under the
		License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR
		CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License for
		the specific language governing permissions and limitations under the
		License.
-->
    
<book lang="en">
	<title>Anyframe Generic Plugin</title>
	
	<bookinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2007-2012</year>
			<holder>Samsung SDS</holder>
		</copyright>
		<releaseinfo>Version 1.5.0</releaseinfo>

		<productname>Anyframe Generic Plugin</productname>
		
		<authorgroup>
			<corpauthor></corpauthor>
		</authorgroup>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="../image/common/logo_pdf.jpg"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<legalnotice>
			<para>
				The copyright of this document is the property of Samsung SDS. Permission is granted to use this document for free only for the purpose of open source community activity.
                The copyright holder should be clearly stated in case this document is copied or distributed, and changed contents should be specified.
                Permission is not granted for the commercial use of the original document and its modification.      
                Should there be parts considered to have errors in this document, please register the issue for which we will take proper action.
			</para>
		</legalnotice>
	</bookinfo>
 
	<part id="generic_introduction_part">
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<partintro id="generic_introduction_partintro">
			<para>
				Anyframe's generic service has been developed based on the <emphasis role="bold">Generics</emphasis> concept supported since Java5, 
				and provides classes that implement all the basic CRUD functions such as Service interface/implementation class based on the domain class and DAO interface/implementation class(supports Hibernate/JPA, Query Service).			
				When applications are developed, classes of Generic service can be used unchanged or inherited to develop additional functions.
				generic plugin is composed of sample codes to guide how to use this generic service and reference libraries.
			</para>		
			<para role="introduction_title"><emphasis role="bold">Installation</emphasis></para>
			<para>Install generic plugin by entering the following command in the Command window.</para>
			<programlisting language="java"><![CDATA[mvn anyframe:install -Dname=generic]]></programlisting>
			<para>
				The installation result can be checked using the installed (mvn anyframe:installed) or the jetty:run (mvn clean jetty:run) commands. 
			</para>
			<para role="introduction_title"><emphasis role="bold">Dependent Plugins</emphasis></para>
			<informaltable>
				<tgroup cols="2">
					<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="5*" />
					<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="5*" />
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry align="center">Plugin Name</entry>
							<entry align="center">Version Range</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry align="center"><ulink url="http://dev.anyframejava.org/docs.en/anyframe/plugin/optional/query/1.5.0/reference/htmlsingle/query.html">query</ulink></entry>
							<entry align="center" valign="middle">2.0.0 > * > 1.4.0</entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</informaltable>		
		</partintro>
	</part>
 	 
	<part id="generic_generic_part">
		<title>Generic</title>
		<partintro id="generic_generic_part_intro">
			<para>
				Generic Service has been revised to fit Anyframe referring to the concept and source codes (including templates) of <ulink url="http://appfuse.org/display/APF/Home">AppFuse Framework</ulink> 
				(http://appfuse.org/display/APF/Home). 
				Samples codes that used classes constituting Generic Service below can be written and used directly, 
				or the codes generated automatically through Anyframe IDE Editor's CRUD generation function can be used.
			</para>
			<para>Development through Generic Service has the following properties.</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Centering on domain model objects basic CRUD codes can be easily created.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Developers can implement basic CRUD functions reusing Service classes and DAo classes provided by Generic Service, not creating Business Layer and Data Access Layer codes.
						
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>When additional functions are needed other than basic CRUD, additional functions can be implemented by inheriting the classes provided by Generic Service.
						
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>It supports Hibernate/JPA and Query Service using DAO Framework.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para> The diagram below is relationship among Generic Service classes. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/generic/generic-flow.jpg" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			The Generic concept is one of the biggest characteristics of Java 5. It means declaring the type of objects to be included in Collection in advance.
			
					What used to be expressed as List list = new ArrayList(); can be expressed as List&lt;String&gt; list = new ArrayList&lt;String&gt;(); by applying Generic,  
		and when objects other than set types, compile errors occur. Thus, casting task is eliminated and readability can improve by clarifying what types to use.
		Also, if Generic type is used, programmers can check errors when compiling so that unintended objects cannot be saved by clarifying wanted object types.
		
		</partintro>
		&generic_implementation_domain;
		&generic_implementation_usage;
		&generic_implementation_test;
		&generic_implementation_resources;
	</part>
</book>